<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on honk.camp</title>
    <link>https://honk.camp/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on honk.camp</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://honk.camp/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Malware Promotion via Fake Forums</title>
      <link>https://honk.camp/p/malware-promotion-via-fake-forums/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://honk.camp/p/malware-promotion-via-fake-forums/</guid>
      <description>Discovering Whilst doing some random googling and looking at some of the last pages, I noticed a recurring pattern in some sites which came up. Then, I noticed this was a method for promoting malware with some interesting ways. This is a writeup on this method.
Forums In case you don&amp;rsquo;t know, forums are a popular form of websites for discussing topics, usually having sites dedicated to certain things like computing, companies / projects (like Mozilla, etc).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Electrum Malware Campaign</title>
      <link>https://honk.camp/p/electrum-malware-campaign/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://honk.camp/p/electrum-malware-campaign/</guid>
      <description>Targeting The main method of targetting users seems to be via a malicious Google Ads campaign. The main site where users seem to be encountering this is Reddit, as seen in this Reddit thread posted. This seems to be executing JS to make an alert telling users to update Electrum and making an executable download via opening another browser (we will talk about how later in the HTML code review). This can be seen in the apparent content of the alert as said in the Reddit thread:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GooseUpdate v3 Codebase Design</title>
      <link>https://honk.camp/p/gooseupdate-v3-codebase-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://honk.camp/p/gooseupdate-v3-codebase-design/</guid>
      <description>GooseUpdate Intro GooseUpdate is an alternative Discord update endpoint which gives users both normal Discord updates with mods (of the user&amp;rsquo;s choice) patched into them automatically. You can find it on GitHub, and also look at the online dashboard.
v3 I started making v3 as the code for GooseUpdate was becoming more complicated and cluttered; since all the code was in one JS file. The idea for v3 was to split it up to be more manageable, plus more easy to maintain and improve in the future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discord&#39;s Telemetry on WebSocket Connect</title>
      <link>https://honk.camp/p/discords-telemetry-on-websocket-connect/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://honk.camp/p/discords-telemetry-on-websocket-connect/</guid>
      <description>Intro Discord uses a WebSocket for communication between their servers and it&amp;rsquo;s web client. I decided to look into it to see if it has any telemetry with their desktop client (even a tiny amount); it does.
The WebSocket WebSocket Intro WebSockets are great for using low bandwidth / data and fast communication, as it is event-driven and can easily support compressed and small messages. They are primarily used in the web, but can also be used server-side for some things.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
